manish.verma217@gmail.com | +91-9958919238

PROFILE

Accomplished Senior Software Developer with 13 years of experience leading projects by acting as architect, developer and programmer analyst • Proficient in supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases • Strong leader in guiding support teams and solving complex issues • Steadfast in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industry best practices.

EDUCATION

SCALER ACADEMY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT May 2022 - Present

RAJIV GANDHI PRODYOGIKI UNIVERSITY

BE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE May 2009 | Bhopal, MP

LINKS

Github:// manishverma LinkedIn:// manishverma LeetCode:// manishverma

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Java

Spring Boot

Spring Data

Data Structures

Algorithm

Git

SQL

Gradle

Postman JUnit

SAP ABAP Workbench

SAP Oil & Gas

SAP Utilities

Familiar:

Linux • MongoDB • Mockito

MANAGERIAL

Quick and Avid Learner Effective Leader Good Team Member

EXPERIENCE

SAP LABS INDIA PVT LTD | SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sept 2015 - Present | Gurugram, HR

- Led a cross-functional team in developing innovative solution that reduced redundancy, and optimized workflow efficiency, resulting in a improvement in 30% overall operational performance.
- Monitored and assessed the progress of trainees, providing personalized guidance and feedback to accelerate their learning curves.
- Successfully executed a strategic data purging process, resulting in a substantial reduction in database size by 70%, enhancing system performance, and contributing to more efficient data management.
- Implemented preventive measures to minimize the occurrence of recurring issues, contributing to a significant 10% reduction in overall downtime.
- Received recognition for playing a key role in the successful incorporation of innovative features, contributing to a 30% increase in user engagement and overall product competitiveness in the market.

HCL TECHNOLOGIES | CONSULTANT

Feb 2014 - Sept 2015 | Noida, UP

PERSONAL PROJECTS

QMONEY | GITHUB LINK

QMoney is a visual stock portfolio analyzer. It helps portfolio managers make trade recommendations for their clients.

- Defined the core logic of the portfolio manager and published it as a library.
- Refactored code to add support for multiple stock quote services.
- Improved application stability and performance.

XMEME | GITHUB LINK

XMeme is a simple backend web application where users can post and see memes.

- Developed XMeme by writing necessary GET and POST APIs for fetching and posting the memes.
- Built the backend application from scratch using a Spring starter template and stored/retrieved the data from MongoDB.
- Tested the application functionality.

OBJECT MODELLING | GITHUB LINK

- Conceived a Hackerrank like contest application by applying Core Java + design skills
- Designed & implemented the classes and business logic required to simulate a contest framework.
- Authored a **JukeBox** application based on a problem statement, from scratch.

AWARDS

- Participated & presented in Life Science AI Hackathon held world over
- 5-Star rating from customers in quality work deliverables
- Product of the year recognized for two consecutive years 2016-17 & 2017-18